<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>pages tagged Bitcoin</title>
<link>http://zander.github.io//tags/Bitcoin/</link>

<description>One may smile, and smile, and be a villain</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 10:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>ClassicQuality</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zander.github.io//posts/ClassicQuality/</guid>

	<link>http://zander.github.io//posts/ClassicQuality/</link>



	<category>Bitcoin</category>


	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 10:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2016-06-30T10:56:22Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started working with Bitcoin, a couple of years ago, I tried
to find out how to contribute code and to understand the Quality Assurance
policies they held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time I naturally was talking to people from the Bitcoin Core group,
and the answers I got were quite confusing to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having worked in the software industry for 20 years I had become very
reliant on good quality assurance policies. As well as good usage of
distributed source management control. Turns out that Core didn&#39;t really
have any of that in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was asked to work with Gavin on Bitcoin Classic I first started to
work on quality assurance policies and practices.  And I&#39;m happy to say that
we have reached at least industry standard, if not a little above. But I
haste to say that there is still room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Git workflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I changed is that we now have a proper git workflow.
This means that developers fix bugs on the stable branch and we use git
merges to make those bugfixes go up to the development branch.
You will find this process in any git book, so I wont&#39; spent too much time
on this.  The important part is that merges between branches is done often
and that way we can&#39;t loose work or introduce bugs by doing it manually.
See also our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoinclassic/bitcoinclassic/blob/develop/CONTRIBUTING.md&quot;&gt;contributing
document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Release process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part that changed is the release process itself.
Based on the fact that we now have a stable branch that is always
releasable the release process will become easier.  The aim is to follow
the good old open source concept of &quot;Release early, release often&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest changes is that we now follow the &lt;a href=&quot;http://semver.org/&quot;&gt;Semantic
Versioning&lt;/a&gt; concept which is almost universal for open
source software as well as for many closed source products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me quote the core concept;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given a version number MAJOR.MINOR.PATCH, increment the:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MAJOR version when you make incompatible API changes,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MINOR version when you add functionality in a backwards-compatible
manner, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PATCH version when you make backwards-compatible bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally I wrote this in the release tag of v1.1.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first we wanted to follow the Core releases, but they have different
core-values and push out hundreds of lines of new code in a bugfix release
which feels dirty to have to inherit.  The result of that is that the CSV
soft fork code feature release has received a bigger version bump.  And
when that disconnect between Core and Classic versions it also stopped
making sense to stay close to versioning of Core.&lt;br /&gt;
It was time to review the numbering scheme altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I talked about the &quot;less than 1.0&quot; versioning over beers with
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eric%5FS%2E%5FRaymond&quot;&gt;Eric S. Raymond&lt;/a&gt; (author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The%5FCathedral%5Fand%5Fthe%5FBazaar&quot;&gt;The Cathedral and the Bazaar&lt;/a&gt;) he explained it like this:&lt;br /&gt;
The idea was that when the app reaches the set of features required
for the user with the lowest demands to use it for its intended usage,
that&#39;s when you call it 1.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, Bitcoin is certainly far past its 1.0 release. We will follow
the Semantic Versioning from now on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Continues Integration building&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was really missing was a proper &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous%5Fintegration&quot;&gt;Continuous integration&lt;/a&gt; (CI) system. Naturally, there is the freely
available Travis.  But thats been a frustrating experience and really not
useful as a build server. Apart from the fact that Travis is really slow
(taking an hour or more), some and 60% of the time when it says there is a
failure, it actually isn&#39;t a problem in our code, its really not useful to
rely on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a dedicated server in a secure environment and installed Teamcity on
it. Teamcity is one of the most used CI software systems out there and
quite useful for our purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zander.github.io//tags/Bitcoin/../../images/teamcity.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://zander.github.io//tags/Bitcoin/../../posts/ClassicQuality/500x500-teamcity.png&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;463&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does a couple of things;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every single time a change is made in Git (in all branches) it builds
this for all platforms and runs unit tests at least for the Linux ones.
Notice that it does the building in a fraction of the time that Travis
took. Typically a build completes in less than 15 min.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It builds both using the &#39;gitian&#39; concept of reproducible (or static)
build environment for all platforms as well as using the native Linux way
of using the platform dynamic-libraries (dlls). This makes sure we know it
works on more than one version of boost and all the other supporting
libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It builds nightly builds of the development branch allowing people to
test these that don&#39;t want to compile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It pushes the build to remote builders (like Ubuntu&#39;s launchpad) to have
an easy way to distribute nightly builds or maybe even future releases with
minimum effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It tests the Debian contrib to actually build properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, the server is in a secure location. What that means is that
it is not connected to the internet and physically protected to make sure
we can trust the output of that server.  When we ship sources anyone can
check quickly if they are unaltered from the tags in git. But with binaries
(evil) changes can be much harder to detect.  So I refuse to gpg-sign any
releases unless I know they actually came from the exact sources that are
in git, visible for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ongoing work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is plenty of issues that could use improvements.  It turns out that
the original developers don&#39;t really like writing unit tests and the code
lacks any organization to make unit testing practical or easy.  With some
small changes such efforts could be made much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have exactly one executable that runs all the test. Which is
against the unit testing practices of having small units because one
failure in one test can cause a lot of tests afterwards to start failing
too, mostly because the memory states were not cleaned up properly after a
failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally we have a lot of small test executables which can be run by a
simple runner. With the added benefit that you can run various in parallel
(one per cpu-core) which makes the whole complete much faster as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currently have a benchmark framework, but nothing in there. The idea of
a benchmark is that code which is time critical can be tested in there and
the output can be printed and plotted over a long time (months) to see that
such time critical code doesn&#39;t get slower by unintended changes from
release to release.&lt;br /&gt;
I find it hard to believe that Bitcoin has no time critical code, as such
we should be able to find value to locate, test and keep code from getting
slower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better integration Linux distro&#39;s. Bitcoin was made to be shipped as a big
executable with all the libraries inside. The thinking was that this saves
the application from misbehaving when another library changes behavior.
While the idea seems logical, it shows a lack of experience because the
open source community has been solving this problem for 30 years and it
does so quite successfully.  Going against that only introduces a different
set of problems.  For instance when the libc DNS exploit was made public
Bitcoin dodged a bullet because libc is one of the very few libraries we
don&#39;t actually compile in. But imagine any of the libraries we include has
such a similar vulnerability and the only way to solve that is to re-build
Bitcoin and get everyone to manually update.   The Linux alternative of
just running an &lt;code&gt;apt-get upgrade&lt;/code&gt; or similar is vastly more secure and
better supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the CI section, I already added support for Classic in
launchpad. This may be something to expand upon and support more Linux
distros in a similar fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Classic has a strong Quality Assurance policy, adopts long time
industry standard practices and sheds unsafe self-invented ones from
upstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also take all the best practices from Open Source and Free Software to
make releases often for those that want to test the latest and contribute
by reporting issues, or simply by being part of the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future is bright!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>On Mining and Wallets</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zander.github.io//posts/On%20Mining%20and%20Wallets/</guid>

	<link>http://zander.github.io//posts/On%20Mining%20and%20Wallets/</link>



	<category>Bitcoin</category>

	<category>Mining</category>


	<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 11:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2016-06-27T11:31:01Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;h3&gt;Don&#39;t leave your money on the street.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoind is labelled as the backend of the network. When I explain this to
friends I explain it like its the router that you have stuffed behind the
sofa or if you are more professional, in a server room, sometimes not even
in the same country you are in.
Either way, it is something needed for everything else to work. But mostly
ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how I imagine the users of Bitcoin Classic to use the software, and
it is the way I think it should be. They use it as something that just
works to make it possible for them to keep their business or infrastructure
running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such group of Bitcoin Classic users are the miners, they run
bitcoin-classic to have an accurate view of the state of the network.  The
new transactions are collected in Bitcoin Classic and it creates new block
templates for them. In short; Bitcoin Classic helps miners connect to the
network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is totally out-of-character with the design that Bitcoin has had for
years is that, when the miner actually mines the block that the
block-reward is &quot;stored&quot; in the Bitcoin node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that your Bitcoin Classic suddenly isn&#39;t just a piece of network
infrastructure anymore.  It holds thousands of dollars worth of value. And
because of that you&#39;d have to protect it.  Which is not always compatible
with the way that you want to use a piece of network infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, the original Bitcoin node that Satoshi made was a reference client and
it included the ability to relay messages, it has a wallet and it knows how
to mine blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years we stopped using the mining software because other software
and hardware solutions have appeared that were much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also seen many better wallets which are much more used than a full
node based wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of those still use the bitcoin full node software, like Bitcoin
Classic, as a platform to build on.  They communicate via various channels
with the Bitcoin software which in turn connects them to the Bitcoin
Network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in my opinion time to separate Bitcoin Mining from the Bitcoin
Wallet. We should no longer force Miners to use the Bitcoin wallet that is
shipped in Bitcoin Classic. We should no longer force the horrible security
practice of storing bitcoin private keys (and the money they represent) on
a piece of equipment that really is meant to be like a router or a hub
connecting your business to the Bitcoin network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Stop demanding a wallet in a mining node&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin Classic&#39;s development branch we have changed the
system to allow mining on a node that does not have a wallet compiled in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I introduced a new RPC command called &lt;code&gt;createaddress&lt;/code&gt;, which returns
something like this;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
{
  &quot;address&quot;: &quot;1E852VpivAYpZcwGo5bNB9U4twjnJfrL2c&quot;,
  &quot;pubkey&quot;:
&quot;0303a60a215af3ea3240705db3201b5161445e1bdbd1e4e942284cfd9e9ede0ea1&quot;,
  &quot;private&quot;: &quot;KyjwYTJrhAS14fV7fP16Z9bhiudpPcSTT5HpPgpoampS57zgT59w&quot;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The private key is the one piece of information needed to later spent the
money that would be stored on the address. To benefit from this change the
miner would store this private key in a secure location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pubkey and the address are not needed to be stored securely, they
can be used in future mined blocks.  When a block is mined with the pubkey
set, the money can later be redeemed using the safely stored private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second new RPC command is &lt;code&gt;setcoinbase&lt;/code&gt;.  When called with the &#39;pubkey&#39;
field from above this will cause any following calls to
&lt;code&gt;getblocktemplate&lt;/code&gt; to be generated so when it is mined all the fees and
block reward will go to the address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can use the output of &lt;code&gt;createaddress&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;or if they don&#39;t like
change, just use the existing &lt;code&gt;getnewaddress&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;validateaddress&lt;/code&gt; rpc
calls to create a coinbase that will end up in your bitcoind wallet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally the command-line option &lt;code&gt;--gencoinbase&lt;/code&gt; is added to bitcoind
which has the same effect as the setcoinbase RPC command and that may be
useful to use until the mining software is upgraded to use these new RPC
commands. Because calling getblocktemplate without setting the coinbase
will now cause an error to be returned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change is still only available on the development branch, and has not
been scheduled for release just yet.  So &lt;strong&gt;there is still time to give
feedback on what you like or dislike or would like to change&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion these changes will have the positive effect that miners can
now feel much more safe when their bitcoind connects them to the bitcoin
network, without needing all the security that a full wallet should have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>
	<title>With Information Comes Understanding</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zander.github.io//posts/With%20Information%20Comes%20Understanding/</guid>

	<link>http://zander.github.io//posts/With%20Information%20Comes%20Understanding/</link>



	<category>Bitcoin</category>

	<category>Community</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 18:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2016-06-27T10:45:43Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;The story I want to tell today is one of confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://zander.github.io//tags/Bitcoin/../../images/escapeTrap.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://zander.github.io//tags/Bitcoin/../../posts/With Information Comes Understanding/400x300-escapeTrap.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/br&gt;&lt;i&gt;Confusing translation. By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/dandownunder/220926841/&quot;&gt;dandownunder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have been a software developer for various decades and in that time the
way that I start a new job or a new task is similar.  It is one of
learning. When I started in a company that creates medical hardware I ended
up spending quite some time reading through books meant for nurses. When I
started in a company that makes a stock-trading platform I had to learn
about the financial industry.  The knowledge of being a software developer
is similar to knowing English or Russian as a novel writer.  It doesn&#39;t
mean you have anything interesting to write.  You need to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I love my profession of software developer. I get to do
something completely different on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning about Bitcoin was surprising difficult. I&#39;ve been learning for
almost 4 years and I am certain I will continue for many more.&lt;br /&gt;
I would have to say that from all the industries that I studied, learning
about Bitcoin details has been the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been talking to quite a lot of people over these years, from forums
like reddit and 8btc to chat, email and VOIP talking to the experts.  I
found that I was not alone with my difficulty of discovering pertinent
details about Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following scenario would happen on a regular basis: A couple of random
people on the internet are in a discussion about some detail. For instance
they talk about the claim that miners would never willingly break the
Bitcoin consensus rules.&lt;br /&gt;
After some time an expert comes in and resolves the conflict by stating
some fact.  In our example, he could say that after the 2012 halving there
were various miners for some hours that continued to mine blocks with 50BTC
reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always wanted to be so wise and learned that I knew all those facts in
the hope that I could become an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin there are currently a very small number of experts. This
generates a handful of problems. The most obvious problem is the one I
outlined above, it makes it hard for new people to enter Bitcoin and become
productive. New people need known experts to help them. Many other problems
are more subtle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problems we face today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the experts having more information than the rest of us,
those experts become authority figures. We need their Ok because we will
likely do things wrong otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a field that spans Economy, Finance, the history of Money,
Psychology, various fields in software architecture (databases,
peer-2-peer networking, cryptography) and probably more. It is impossible
for any one person to be an expert in all of those.  Yet, when we talk to
our Bitcoin experts I never once heard any of them say that they would
rather defer to someone more knowledgeable than themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discussions about Bitcoin can be about opinions or about well researched
facts.  In the current world it is impossible to differentiate fact from
opinion because we can&#39;t independently validate those facts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have become convinced that the first big step we need to make to create
a more healthy Bitcoin ecosystem is to make access to currently well hidden
facts completely open for anyone to access and contribute to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikimedia &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Vision&quot;&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world in which every single human being can freely share in the
sum of all knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that goal is inspiration that Bitcoin could use very well.  I would
like to see a Free Wikipedia for Bitcoin technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are quite a number websites today that have a small amount of
information, typically on one topic for one specific group of users. For
instance people new to Bitcoin. But nothing that combines those ideas and
facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special mention should go to the bitcoin.it website which has a lot of
in-depth information.  Unfortunately most of it is hopelessly outdated and
looking through the discussions it becomes obvious this is because it has
been strictly guarded by a small number of people that would remove without
discussion any opinions not already known to them. This kind of behavior
is the death to cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secondary goal, then, should be to create documentation that can not
be censored or controlled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;BitcoinWiki.git&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Part of the solution; git.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git is a tool used for many years by enthusiasts and professionals alike to
create a distributed
&lt;a href=&quot;http://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/&quot;&gt;workflow&lt;/a&gt;.
Anyone can create changes and offer them to the world to accept or reject
based on merit only.  Git allows anyone to start contributing without
permission. It also removes the central ownership. No longer is it needed
to convince one group of the worth of your changes, there may be various
groups each creating what they think is the best version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Lowering the threshold of entry.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While git allows the actual required working together, it is just a basic
layer. Many end users don&#39;t want to use git, and that should be perfectly
Ok.&lt;br /&gt;
Much like Wikipedia allows a user to do everything from a web browser, we
need a way to do the same in order to not scare off people that could
really contribute but don&#39;t have the technical knowledge to install and use
tools on their machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my search for a solution I found a tool called
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ikiwiki.info/&quot;&gt;ikiwiki&lt;/a&gt;. This is a tool that combines the concept
of a wiki and the concept of distributing control using git.
What one person changes on the website can be merged with what another
person makes at another time. Even when those people use a different
website or a different team to do the work in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Starting the revolution.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start somewhere I present a website that has all the content (including
all revisions back until its start in 2010) copied from what has so far
been the main Bitcoin wiki. I put them online for now at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://bitcoinfactswiki.github.io&quot;&gt;bitcoinwiki.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. This is a simple
website and editing is currently disabled.
The wiki database is converted to be
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt;, which is a more modern
alternative than the old wiki used. This is also the native format that
ikiwiki uses. Don&#39;t worry, you likely are not going to have problems with
it as you may already know it quite well. Markdown is used at many places
like
&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/getting-started-with-writing-and-formatting-on-github/&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;
and Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://BitcoinFactsWiki.github.io&quot;&gt;bitcoinwiki.github.io&lt;/a&gt; is the current
version, the complete history is found in git on github
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BitcoinFactsWiki/english&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even with the full historical content, I do believe we need some heros
to step up and do some major work. Many pages are hopelessly outdated and
there are quite a lot of flaws in the actual content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to that, many pages use rendering-templates that have not been ported
over to the git repository. I would suspect that most of them are in fact
irrelevant. Some closer inspection is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Be part of the solution, please help&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my own humble opinion the goal of the old wiki is wrong, it highlighted
all companies in the space which included all gambling sites and places
selling hardware. This is fast-changing information and frankly serves
nobody but the companies.  Likewise, pages about people feel out of place.
It so quickly becomes about being better than anyone else. I don&#39;t have a
wikipedia page and I think I&#39;m better off without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actual technical information, backgrounds, overviews and historical facts
would be useful to write down. In my opinion it should be a source of
information where fresh content is shared and research published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need people to go in and slice up the bad stuff, move pages to better
locations and move out useless content. I have already spent too much time,
time I could spend on writing better Bitcoin code. So I hope others can
pick up the baton and fork my the bitcoinwiki project on github and work on
making it ready for more and more people to come in add their work and
content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the title of this blogposts, sharing how Bitcoin works and
sharing knowledge about many of its darker corners will allow the
conversation to shift back into a less emotional one.  It is always easier
to discuss topics when opinions are not confused with facts and facts are
not fought with opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
